# **Rahul Arora**

GFG | LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode

Location: Gurgaon, Haryana, India Email: rahul.012.arora@gmail.com | Mobile: 8383092280

## **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Hello, I am a passionate Web developer with knowledge/project experience in **JAVA**, **JavaScript**, **HTML**, **and CSS**, and have developed web applications using React.js and vanilla js. I like to constantly learn and stay up-to-date with the latest industry trends.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
Frameworks : React.js, Express, Node.js

**Libraries** : Material, Ant Design, React Router

**Databases** : MongoDB

**Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, Git, Github

# **EXPERIENCE**

Process EngineerAug 2021 – Aug 2022Carrier India LimitedGurgaon, Haryana, India

Led Design development and Topology Study using SolidWorks & Pro-E

• Automation projects for Assembly Line & Time study

### **INTERNSHIPS & CERTIFICATIONS**

Newton School
Aug 2022 – Present
Full-Stack Web Developer
Remote

- Technical Stack Learnt: Data Structures And Algorithms(JAVA), React, Javascript, HTML, CSS & Bootstrap.
- · Worked on MERN Stack Web Apps.
- Worked on Rest API and Https protocols.

Carrier India Ltd.Jan 2021 – July 2021Design & Process EngineerGurgaon, Haryana, India

- Led the design for Automation of coil assembly processes to reduce takt time.
- Undertook Time Study to determine inefficiencies in processes.

#### **EDUCATION**

# JC Bose University(Formerly Y.M.C.A)

Bachelor of Technology (Mechanical Engineering)

S.N.S.P.S Public School

PCM 95.2%

Faridabad, Haryana, India Jul 2017 – Aug 2021

Gurgaon, Haryana, India April 2014 – April 2015

# **PROJECTS**

## Admin dashboard planner

React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.

Source Code

- Used useState, useEffect hooks for creating dynamic features.
- Use of an external API and libraries.
- Provides users to view analysis of data & provide functionality to plan tasks.

# **Disney Hotstar UI Clone**React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap. Source Code

- · Users can hover on feed elements to view movie/show details
- User have auto-scrolled tabs on the top & carousel options on 3 different categories in feed